（不動(ふどう) 明(あきら)）
違う！ 俺は悪魔なんかじゃない
No! I'm not a demon!
（銃声）
（明）あっ…
（ミーコ）はっ…
（ガビ）ヒエ？
Hie?
I'm not a demon.
俺は悪魔じゃない…
人間 不動 明だ
I'm Akira Fudo. A human.
（ミーコ）んっ…
（明）美樹(みき)！
Miki.
（ワム）来るな 牧村(まきむら)！
-Stay back, Makimura.
-Trust me, Miki.
信じてくれ 美樹！
俺はずっと…
ずっと悪魔と戦ってきた
I've been fighting against
the demons this whole time.
人間を守るために……
悪魔になった この体を使って
To protect the humans,
I've been using my body
that merged with a demon.
（ガビ）ほら 悪魔だ
-See, he's a devil.
-Trust me.
信じてくれ！
心は人間のままなんだ
-I still have the heart of a human.
-Bullshit.
（ワム）ふざけんじゃねえよ
There's no way I'd kill a human.
（明）人を殺すなんてありえない
あれは俺じゃないはずだ！
俺が人を殺すなんて
There's no way that was me.
I'd never kill a human.
（ガビ）確証ないのか
（明）あっ…
But you're not sure.
（ガビ）
だから牧村にも秘密だったんだな
That's why you
kept it from Makimura, right?
（明）んっ…
（ワム）おい 近づくな 牧村！
-Don't go near him, Makimura.
-He's a devil.
（ガビ）そいつは悪魔だ！
（牧村美樹）あの時もそうだった
You were the same back then, too.
明君 さっきも
家族のために泣いてくれたよね
Akira, you were crying
for my family earlier, weren't you?
は… あ…
明君は変わらない
You haven't changed, Akira.
ありがとう 美樹…
Thanks, Miki.
We are family, after all.
だって家族だろ？
（ガビ）はあ…
ん…
（パトカーのサイレン）
（明）あっ！
（ミーコ）来た！
They're here.
（ガビ）ん… はえーな
That was quick.
You, get out.
お前は出てけ
頼んだぞ
I'm counting on you.
俺は了(りょう)に会わなければならない
I have to go meet Ryo.
But, Akira...
明君 でも…
必ず美樹の元へ戻る
I'll come back to you, Miki.
はあ… 約束だぞ
君がアンカーだからな
That's a promise.
You are the anchor, after all.
おう
Yup.
（警察無線）不動明を牧村邸で確認
近隣住民から通報あり
We received a tip that
Akira Fudo's at the Makimura residence.
応援送れ！ 相手は悪魔だ
We need backup.
This is a devil.
（警官１）
牧村一家 不動明を出せ！
Makimura family, give us Akira Fudo.
かくまっても無駄だぞ！
It's useless to protect him.
（警官２）悪魔だ！
-A devil!
-There he is!
（警官３）出たぞ！
（銃声）
（警官４）追え！ 逃がすな！
Don't let him get away!
GO TO HELL, YOU MORTALS
（スタッフ）はい カット！
And, cut.
Humans are weak
when it comes to authorities.
（雷沼(らいぬま)デーモン）人間というヤツは
権威に弱いから―
今のデマを信じるだろう
They'll believe the lie.
（デーモンたちの笑い声）
（ゼイ）どちらへ？
-Where to?
-Back to my place.
（飛鳥(あすか) 了）マンションに戻る
これで明は
私の所へ来るしかなくなった
Now Akira doesn't have a choice
but to come to me.
幸田(こうだ)！
Koda.
Why?
（デビルマン）
なぜだ… なぜだ 了！
Why, Ryo?
（民衆１）おら この野郎！
（民衆２）撃っちまえ！
-You fool!
-Die!
-Hurry up!
-Die! You devil!
（民衆３）早く死ね！
（民衆４）死ねー！
（民衆５）悪魔め！
（民衆６）パパを返せ！
-Daddy!
-Give me my daughter!
-Devil!
-Die!
（民衆の怒声）
Die!
Stop it.
（デビルマン）やめろ！
（眼鏡）ひゃああ
（民衆８）悪魔だ！
-A devil.
-Are you on his side?
（民衆９）かばう気だ
（民衆10）助けに来た
-He's come to save them.
-The guy from TV.
（眼鏡）テレビのヤツだ
（民衆12）テレビで見たぞ！
I saw you on TV!
（民衆13）警察 呼べ！
-Call the police!
-It's Akira Fudo!
（民衆14）不動明だ！
うっ
俺はデビルマンだが
こいつらは ただの人間だ！
I'm a Devilman,
but they're just humans.
人間が人間を殺すのか！ くっ…
Are you humans gonna kill other humans?
-Kill him!
（民衆の怒声）
That's enough!
いいかげんにしろ！
こいつらが本当に悪魔だったら
お前らなんか一撃で殺せるんだぞ
If they were really demons,
you'd all be killed in one blow.
今 車 取り行ってっから
戻ったら すぐここを離れる
We're getting in the car right now.
We'll leave as soon as it gets here.
人殺しはしない
I won't be a murderer.
はあ…
じゃあ これもらっといてくれ
（美樹）ん…
Well, then hold on to this.
（ワム）ヒーローのお守りだ
世話になった人にもらったんだ
It'll protect you. It's from someone
who looked after me.
You sure?
いいの？
-Do you think it'll work?
-Of course.
効くかな？
無敵さ
Then I wish I could have lent it to Akira.
そんなら 明君に
貸してあげたかったな
何か二度と会えないような
気がして
I feel like I'll never see him again.
あんたらしくねえな
信じろ あいつのこと
It's not like you to say that.
Believe in him.
And believe in that bling, too.
そのピアスの力も
-Try killing me!
-Die!
（民衆１）殺してみろ！
（民衆２）死ね！
（眼鏡）人間なめんな！
-Your time is over!
-I won't kill humans!
人は殺さない
俺も人間だからだ！
Because I'm also a human!
（民衆３）殺してたろ！
（銃声）
（デビルマン）うっ！
人を… 人を殺すなー！
Don't! Don't kill humans!
（民衆たち）わあっ！
俺は… 俺の心は人間なんだ！
I have the heart of a human.
Why are humans fighting one another?
何で人間同士でいがみ合う！
殺し合うんだ！
Why kill each other?
If you're going to kill, kill a demon.
殺すなら悪魔を殺せ！
俺を殺せ！
Kill me.
Why do you kill each other?!
何で殺し合う！
憎しみ合うんだ！
Why do you hate each other?!
（民衆４）何だ？
-What?
-Is he crying?
（民衆５）泣いてんのか？
（民衆６）痛かったか
-Did it hurt?
-He cried. He cried!
（眼鏡）泣いた 泣いたよ
（民衆７）ハハッ
-Strange fluid's coming out of his eyes.
-Do devils have hearts, too?
（民衆８）泣いてんのか
（民衆９）目から変な汁出た
悪魔にも心があんのか
-Don't be fooled.
-He's a devil!
（民衆10）だまされんな
（民衆11）こいつ悪魔だぞ！
（民衆の怒声）
Good evening, everyone.
Today I would like
to talk about someone important to me.
Akira Fudo.
A lot of you probably just saw him on TV.
He is my family.
Akira said he's not a demon.
He is a Devilman.
He has the body of a demon,
but the heart of a human.
I believe him.
I think his heart hasn't changed.
He cries for other people.
He's always been like that,
since he was little.
He cried for me when I couldn't cry
because I was being stubborn.
When Akira cries,
it's always for someone else.
He doesn't cry at all
when he's sad himself.
He's strong.
He has a strong heart.
But he mostly cries for other people.
（民衆１）悪魔 死ねー！
（民衆２）人間なめんな！
If more people
in the world were like Akira...
I think everyone would be happy.
Crying for other people...
and thinking about other people.
That might just be a fantasy.
But...if it's a person
with a heart like that...
whether they are demon or human...
I'll accept them.
And love them unconditionally.
はあ…
Peace will come if everyone believes that.
Even if I'm powerless on my own.
Even if each of us is powerless.
If we all believed that...
the world would change in a second.
“私もデビルマンです”
はっ！
（民衆１）おい あれ
Hey, that...
（民衆２）
やめろ そいつは悪魔だぞ
Stop. He's a demon.
ん…
“あなたの勇気に
敬意を表します”
Devilman my ass
Must have a death wish
（民衆３）おい！
（民衆４）あれ！
んっ ああ…
FOUND A DEVIL
SAME PERSON?
CHECK THE IP ADDRESS
（民衆５）だまされるか！
（民衆６）悪魔め！
We won't be fooled. You devil!
（民衆７）バカ こっち来い！
Stupid! Traitor!
（民衆８）裏切り者だ！
もろとも殺せー！
DIE! LIAR!
I'M ALSO A DEVILMAN
I'M A DEVILMAN TOO
HUMAN HEARTS ARE EQUAL
THERE'S NO HUMAN?
I WANT TO BELIEVE TOO
I TOLD MY WIFE I'M A DEVILMAN
I will believe you.
（男１）信じるよ
（女１）ありがとう
Thank you.
（女２）ごめんなさいね
I'm so sorry.
So sorry. Sorry about that.
ごめんなさい
（男２）悪かった
（女３）ごめんね
（男３）すまん
（女４）うう… うう…
（男４）おい
（男５）あっ…
（男４）ほら
（男６）あっ…
（了）ふっ…
Hey, Devilman.
（幸田）よう デビルマン
（幸田マン）うああ！
（民衆のざわめき）
The world belongs to the demons.
世界は悪魔のものだ
（デビルマン）ぐおわああ！
（幸田マン）ガアア！
Good job, Koda.
Move, we'll finish it off.
（デーモン）よくやった幸田
どいてろ とどめだ！
やめろー！
This way.
こっちだ！
（幸田マン）チッ！
（デビルマン）ううっ…
（デーモン）ウガッ
ガアア
ウガー！
（デビルマン）ううっ
（ゼノン）ガァハ
（デビルマン）ぐうっ！
うわああ
（ゼノン）ぶあ… ぐあ！
うがああ！
おああああー
（デビルマン）うううう！
（ゼノン）があああ
What's the holdup?
おせえな
DEVILMAN
I wanted to beat you
in track-and-field,
（ミーコ）陸上で―
美樹に勝ちたかったけど
かなわなかった
but I was never able to.
（美樹）また次の機会あるよ
You'll get another chance.
I've always...
ずっと… 美樹のこと嫌いだった
hated you, Miki.
あ…
（ミーコ）ずっと１番だった
私の立場 奪った
I was always the best,
but you took that away.
うん
私もミキなのに―
Even though I'm Miki,
あんたと一緒にいたら
ミーコって呼ばれるようになった
people started to call me Miko around you.
（美樹）うん
取材もいっぱい来た
“美樹ちゃんの友達ですか？”
I got asked in a lot of interviews
if I was your friend.
“美樹ちゃんのこと
教えてください”
They wanted me to tell them about you.
“美樹ちゃんはどう思うかな？”
About what you thought.
You're beautiful, popular, fashionable,
美人で人気者でセンスよくて
いいヤツで何でも１番
and the best at everything.
Always the best. I hated you.
１番１番… ホント ヤなヤツ
ホント 大っ嫌いだった
I seriously hated you.
うん…
知ってた
I knew that.
でも… 大好きだった
But I loved you.
I knew that, too.
それも知ってた
私… ずっと分からなかった
I didn't know this whole time.
ミーコ 今かっこいい
前のミーコも好きだったけど
Miko, you're so cool now.
But I liked you how you were before, too.
（ミーコ）ごめん…
I'm sorry.
（ガラスが割れる音）
（美樹）あっ…
（暴徒１）牧村美樹の家だ！
（暴徒２）悪魔の家！
It's Miki Makimura's house!
Witch's house! Devil!
（暴徒３）
悪魔！ 不動明をかくまっていた
（ガラスが割れる音）
-Get weapons.
-They're from the neighborhood.
牧村 武器を用意しろ！
近所の人たちよ
（ターコ）ギャオ
Tako!
（美樹）ターコ！
つきあいは
賞味期限切れらしいぜ
Relationships don't last forever.
Go upstairs. I'll stop them.
３階へ逃げろ！ 食い止める
（ドアをたたく音）
（暴徒１）いたぞっ！
Kill them!
（ワム）おらっ
（ガビ）クッ… クッ…
（ワム）うう… ううう
（ワム･ガビ）うおっ！
（暴徒２）うひゃひゃ… あっ
あああ… うっ…
（暴徒３）へへへ
（ガビ）入ってくんな こら！ おら
Don't come in!
（ワム）ぬう…
-Wamu!
-Miki.
ワム！
（ミーコ）美樹！
（ガラスが割れる音）
（美樹）死ぬなよ ヒーロー！
Don't die, hero.
Get outside if you want to live!
死にたくねえヤツは
外に出ろ！
（明）美樹！ 戻るよ 君の所へ
Miki.
I'm coming back to you.
俺は君から
一番 大切なものを受け取った
I got the most important thing
of all from you.
俺が人間であり続けるのは
君がいるからだ
I can remain a human because you exist.
（暴徒１）くっ 魔女め！
You witch!
（美樹）えいっ！
（暴徒２）魔女いたぞ
There's that witch.
（暴徒３）外人め！
-You outsider.
-That's right. I'm different from you all.
そうよ あんたたちとは違う
（暴徒４）魔女め
（美樹）私は…
-You witch!
-I'm...
-Witch!
-A witch!
（暴徒５）魔女！
（美樹）魔女よ！
（暴徒６）わあー！
はっ
（暴徒６）わあ
（暴徒７）魔女だ！
（暴徒８）魔女 屋根に逃げたぞ
-It's that witch!
-She's on the roof!
（美樹）ミーコ！
Miko.
（ミーコ）ごめん 私の背中
乗ってくれる？
Sorry. Will you ride on my back?
うん！
Yes.
What are you going to do?
どうするの？
（ミーコ）飛ぶ！
（美樹）えっ？
Fly.
-By the river!
-Follow them!
（暴徒９）逃げた！
（暴徒10）河原のほうだ！
（暴徒11）追え！
（暴徒12）逃げたぞ！
They escaped!
（暴徒12）おおっ
（暴徒13）なんだこいつ
What is this?
（ターコ）ニャー！
（暴徒たち）うわっ！
（ガビ）ッツ… 邪魔すんな！
Don't bother.
う～ おっ！ おわっ！
（暴徒）てめ…
（ガビ）ふんっ！ はあ はあ…
へっ どうしたい
Your move.
あ… う…
（暴徒）へっへっへ
（ガビ）なんで… ぐがっ…
Why?
（暴徒）ひゃっほー！
The thing I want to protect
the most is you, Miki.
（明）俺が一番 守りたいもの
それは美樹 君だ！
待ってろ！ 今 行く！
Hang on. I'm coming.
明のヤツ… 遅いな
Akira's taking a long time.
（ミーコ）ここ よく走ったね
いっつも走ってたね！
We used to run here often, didn't we?
We were always running.
（美樹）よく練習した！
We practiced a lot.
I used to always chase after you.
You were good at everything.
（ミーコ）私は何でもできる
あんたをいつも追いかけてた
私 あんた大好きだから！
I love you!
私もー！
I love you, too!
（銃声）
Miko!
（美樹）ミーコ！
（ミーコ）走るの好き！
I love running!
（美樹）私も好き！
I love running, too!
（ミーコ）走れてよかった
I'm glad we ran.
（銃声）
ぐっ… ん… ミーコ！
Miko!
（ミーコ）美樹 走れ！
Miki! Run!
走れ 美樹！
Run, Miki!
走れ 美樹ー！
美樹ー！ ファイトー！
Miki!
Go!
Miko!
ミーコ！
（暴徒１）おぞましいな
（暴徒２）悪魔め
-Disgusting.
-You devil.
-Where's the witch?
-Is she running?
（暴徒３）魔女は？
（暴徒４）走ってんのか
あんたたちに問う
Let me ask you this.
What is it?
（暴徒１）何だよ
What does it mean to be human?
What does it mean to be good?
人間らしくあることとは！
善良であることとは！
（暴徒５）死ぬなら早く死ねよ
-If you're gonna die, hurry up.
-What is justice? What is right?
正義とは！ 正しいこととは！
（暴徒３）悪魔は死ぬべきだろ
Devils should die.
牧村美樹を助けて！
Save Miki Makimura!
（暴徒３）死ねよ 早く
-Hurry up and die.
-Die already.
（暴徒４）早く死ね！
Please, let her live.
お願い！ 彼女を生かして
Please!
頼む！
（銃声）
（美樹）
何で走るのか？
理屈は分からない
Why do I run?
I don't know the reason.
I just like to.
好きだから… ちょっとでも
ほんの少しでも前へ
Even just a little,
just a tiny bit farther.
If I go forward,
I feel like something will change.
前へ進めば
何かが変わる気がする
取るに足らない
ほんの少しでも
It's trivial.
Even if it's just a little bit.
Even just a little.
Even the smallest bit.
ちょっとでも
ほんのちょっとでも
（荒い息）
（銃声）
ぐっ… はあ はあ はあ…
Akira! I have to pass you the baton!
明君！ あなたに
バトン渡さなきゃ！
（美樹の荒い息）
はっ… ワム！
Wamu!
はあっ…
くっ… は…
Akira.
（中学生の美樹）
明君… バトン… 明君
The baton.
Akira.
（美樹）バトン
ぎやあああああああ！
美樹 戻ってきたよ！
Miki, I'm back.
美樹！
Miki.
（デビルマン）はっ！
は… は… はっ…
あ… ああ… ああああ
あ… ぐう… うああ…
You guys are the ones who are demons.
悪魔だ… お前たちこそ
地獄へ落ちろ！
Go to hell,
人間どもめー！
you mortals!
&lrm;日本語字幕　後藤 太郎
Subtitle translation by
SDI